每个病人的故事都有同样的开始
Every patient's story starts the same way...
原本十分健康
It starts with them being fine.
此刻  健康已成往事
It starts in the before
人们却执着于那一刻
they cling to this moment
曾经健康的一刻
This memory of being fine
执着于过去
This before...
别担心
Don't worry.
希望能借此找回健康
As though talking about it might somehow bring it back.
好久不见
It have been a long time.
特护病床已经准备好了
We've got an I. C. U. Bed all ready for him.
却没有料到
But what they don't realize is that
他们将过去的健康往事  向我们诉说
the fact that they're talking about it to us，
向他们的医生诉说
Their doctors...
他昨天还好好的
Yesterday he was fine.
午餐时我还觉得他没事
We went to lunch. I thought he was fine.
意味着  健康已逝
Means there's no going back.
当他们来到我们面前
By the time they see us...
便已进入病后生活
They're already in the after.
你在瞎摆弄些什么
What the hell are you doing?
实习医生们崩溃了
The interns are broken.
他们因自行摘除阑尾而受罚
They've been punished for taking out their own appendixes
并因此开始讨厌医学
And it's making them hate medicine.
他们现在很迷茫  他们忘记了
They're lost right now and they've forgotten
他们所讨厌的事
That this thing they hate
其实是他们真正热爱的事业
Is actually a thing they love
所以我打算提醒一下他们
So I'm gonna remind them.
是因为丹尼吗
Is this about Denny?
这是针对男友过失的艺术疗法
Is this some kind of dead-boyfriend art therapy?
这事和丹尼无关
This is not about Denny.
这是为了那些实习医生们
It's about the interns.
谁会在乎那些实习医生  他们只是一堆废物
Who cares about the interns?They're a bunch of losers.
他们不是
They're not!
他们不是  他们只是...
They're not. They're just...
他们需要一些乐趣
Oh! They need to have a little fun
我也一样
And so do I.
该死的剪刀哪去了
Where are the damn scissors?
就在你面前
They're right in front of you.
好吧
Right.
伊兹
Lz.
能把那个递给我一下吗
Will you hand me that large bowel, please?
好了  放这儿  你看
Okay. Just put it down. See?
相当不错吧
It's gonna be great.
他知道自己怎么惹上寄生虫的吗
Does he know how he got the parasite?
他认为他是因为
He thinks he got it
在墨西哥吃了没洗过的水果
From eating unwashed fruit in Mexico.
他心率减慢了
He's bradycardic.
为什么他会心率减慢和血压降低
Why is he bradycardic and hypotensive?
他对止痛点滴有反应
He's having a reaction to the fentanyl drip.
停止点滴  加入盐酸烯丙羟吗啡酮
Stop the fentanyl drip and push the narcan.
等等  德克  他一直都这样
Wait. Derek. He was in status.
我的意思是  你如果停掉点滴的话
I mean. If you take him off the drip and he's seizes up
会对他大脑造成永久性伤害
There could be permanent brain damage.
我们最好祈祷那不会发生
We better hope that doesn't happen.
祈祷  那就是你的计划吗  仅仅祈祷
Hope? That--that's what your plan is--is hinging on
那最坏的结果不会发生吗
Hoping that--that the worst doesn't happen?
没错  我祈祷他不再痉挛
Yeah. I'm hoping he's stopped seizing
因为我知道如果我们不停止点滴
Because I know if we don't reverse the drip
他就再醒不过来了
His heart is going to arrest.
你有什么更好的办法吗
So unless you have a better idea...
注射盐酸烯丙羟吗啡酮
Push the narcan
尽管每个病人的故事
And while every patient's story
都有一个同样的开始
Starts the same way...
但故事的结局却掌握在我们手中
How the story ends depends on us
掌握在每一次诊断和治疗中
On how well we diagnosis and treat.
我们知道  一切由我们决定
We know the story hinges on us...
发生室颤  把急救车推来
He's in v-fib. Get the crash cart.
并且我们都想成为英雄
And we all want to be the hero.
早上好  头儿
Morning Chief.
我听说来了个病人脑子里有寄生虫
I heard there was a guy here with worms in his brain.
有人知道治疗脑寄生虫的方法吗
Does anyone know the medical term for worms in the brain?
斯蒂芬教授今天要你们参加一个特殊项目
Dr. Stevens requested you today for a special project.
好了  每人拿一个信封
Okay. Take an envelope and then pass the rest back
但都别打开它们
But do not open them.
你们将需要它们
You're gonna need them
来玩我们今天的第一个游戏
For the first game we're gonna play.
那就是我们今天要做的吗  玩游戏
That's what we're doing today. Playing games?
开心点
Cheer up.
将会很有意思的
We are gonna have so much fun.
我说了  不要打开信封
I said don't open the envelope!
你难道连一个简单的游戏都不会玩吗
Don't you know how to play a simple game?
-我8岁就会玩了  -还是让我们开始吧
- I did when I was 8. - Let's just go.
今天贝利医生要和艾迪森一起
Dr. Bailey's with Addison today
所以由我来分配你们早上的任务
So I'm gonna hand out your morning assignments.
艾迪森在医院里吗
Addison's in the hospital?
他弟弟昨晚被查出
Her brother was admitted last night
脑中有寄生虫
With parasites in his brain.
艾迪森的弟弟脑中有神经囊虫
Addison's brother has neurocysticercosis?
听见了没
See?
这才是我要的
That's what I'm talking about.
我推掉了所有的事
I cleared my schedule.
你不必这样做的  我很好
Oh You didn't have to do that. I'm--I'm fine.
你弟弟脑子里有寄生虫
Your brother has parasites in his brain.
所以我要推掉其他事  你剪头发了
I cleared my schedule. You cut your hair.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
我喜欢
I like it.
我是玛兰达·贝利医生  -哦  抱歉
- Uh Dr. Miranda Bailey. - Oh I'm sorry.
这位是米兰达  这位是内阿密
Um Miranda Naomi. Naomi Miranda
内阿密是海边健康中心的专家
Naomi's our fertility uh specialist
我最铁的朋友之一
Down at oceanside wellness and one of my oldest friends.
很高兴见到你  米兰达  他如何了
It's nice to meet you, Miranda. So how is he?
我不知道
I don't know.
他还在昏迷  他的眼睛睁着但我不认为他醒了
He's groggy. His eyes are open but I don't think he's awake
因为他并没有要杀我
Because he hasn't tried to kill me.
他弟弟很恨我
Her brother hates me.
人们会在别人离婚后选择站在哪边  德里克
People pick sides in a divorce. Derek.
离婚前他就选择好了
He picked sides in the marriage.
他首次痉挛发生时  正与女友水深火热中
He first seized during sex with his girlfriend.
我在想为什么她不在这儿
I wonder why she's not here.
她在的
Oh She is.
内阿密
Naomi?
我要进去了
I'm going in there.
你和阿尔奇吗
You and Archer?
不  噢  是的
No. Uh Well Yeah.
我是说  我  我不知道
I mean I don't--I don't know.
是的  我不知道  我不知道我们怎么了
Yeah I don't know. I don't know what we are.
萨姆怎么样了
How's Sam?
萨姆很好
Sam's good.
那么  梅丽迪斯怎么样了  她是这么叫的吗
And uh How's Um... Meredith... is that her name?
她很好
She's good.
那就好
Good.
是啊
Yeah.
行了  看看我们
Well. Look at us.
我们就傻站在这儿
We're standing here.
礼礼貌貌地讨论着你的女朋友
Making polite conversation about your girlfriend.
你们俩分手了  我和萨姆也分手了
You two are divorced. Me and Sam are divorced
我和阿尔奇好了
And I'm with Archer sort of.
到底怎么了
What the hell happened?
我是说  你写了首歌给艾迪森  德里克
I mean, You--you wrote Addison a song, Derek.
你能别提那首歌吗
Can we just forget about the song?
我受够那首歌了
Enough about the song.
什么  你写了首她喜欢的歌
What? You wrote her her own love song
而且你在婚礼上唱给她听
And you sang it to her at the wedding.
那是马克或者萨姆写的  或者别的什么人
Mark wrote it or sam--somebody.
-我记不清是谁了  -我记得
- I don't remember who it was. - I do. I do.
我那时喝醉了  但我还记得
I was drunk at the time but I remember
而且我还以为你们会一辈子在一起
And I remember thinking you guys were gonna last forever
-大家都会一辈子在一起  -是啊
- That we were all gonna last forever. - Yeah.
你该给萨姆打个电话  他很想你
You should call Sam. He misses you.
好的
Yeah.
睡得怎么样
How'd you sleep?
不太好
Not too well.
因为肩膀疼吗
Shoulder pain?
-不是  因为有个烦人的妻子  -不
- No. Pain-in-the-ass wife. - No
我让他陪了我整晚  因为我担心
I kept him up all night because I was afraid
我的动脉瘤会爆炸  我会就这样死了
My aneurysm was gonna explode and I was gonna die.
你好  我是克莱夫医生
Hi, I'm Dr. Karev.
格蕾医生去哪了
Well. Where's Dr. Grey?
她说过她要替我做手术的
She's supposed to be in my surgery.
她和谢博德医生去处理急救去了
Uh she and Dr. Shepherd got called in on an emergency.
看起来他一时半会处理不了你的动脉瘤了
So it looks like he's not gonna get to your aneurysm until later.
那要什么时候
Wh--later when?
可能几小时后  可能明天
Could be a few hours. It could even be tomorrow.
明天
Tomorrow?
她已经为今天准备好了啊  今天就是明天
I mean She's already waited till tom--today is tomorrow.
-抱歉  你是谁  -我是她丈夫
- I'm sorry. Who are you?  - I'm her husband.
我这副德行是因为
Oh I look like this because--
我开车碾到了他
I ran him over with our car
现在才得知我脑子里有颗炸弹
Before i knew i had this huge time bomb in my head
而我则是个晚育的母亲
When i was just a big ol' pregnant person
等着宝宝出世
Waiting for her baby.
所以  如果谢博德医生能够
So... Just, please, if Dr. Shepherd could, you know
早点来  而不是晚来
Get to me sooner Rather than later.
发生什么紧急情况了
What's the emergency?
艾迪森的哥哥
Addison's brotr.
艾迪森在这儿
Addison's here?
我们正吃晚饭  他突然昏过去了
We were having dinner, And he just passed out.
我告诉你  可能只是疝气而已
I am telling you, it is Probably just my hernia.
他患有腹股沟疝
Uh, he has An inguinal hernia
但看来不是阻塞的原因
But it doesn't seem to be The source of the obstruction.
宝贝  看来两位医生
You know, honey, it's gonna Take these doctors
还需一些时间才能确诊
A long time to figure this out, All right?
我很好  你赶紧去工作吧
I am fine here. Now you gotta go to work.
他不喜欢别人帮他
He hates it when we try to help him.
他就像个小孩一样
He's a lot like My second graders that way.
老爸  你赢了  我手机开着
Okay, daddy, you win. And i have my cell.
需要时打我电话
So call me if you need me.
好的  再见
Okay. Bye.
我得了结直肠癌
I have colorectal cancer.
三年内去除了五块息肉
I've had five polyps removed In the last three years
还做过放疗
And radiation.
我没让女儿知道  希望你们也别说
My daughter doesn't know And i would like To keep it that way.
杨医生会为你做断层扫描对比
Dr. Yang is gonna set you up For a c. t. With contrast.
你在哪里接受治疗的
Where have you been treated?
我们需要以前的病例
We'll need to get Your medical records.
维罗纳的哥伦比亚医院  秀尔特医生
Columbia hospital in verona, And dr. Shulty.
我
I, uh...
我转来这里工作了
I work here now.
我看到你来了  我想
I saw that you were in And i thought i--
等她走了再进来打招呼
You waited till she left To come in and say hello.
你就是这样面对旧事的  一个大男人
That's just like you to face up To things like a man.
你该告诉她癌症的事  迈克尔
You should really tell her About the cancer, michael.
她该知道
She deserves to know.
你没资格跟我谈她
You lost the right to tell me anything about her
你发来邮件说你取消订婚的时候你就没资格了
When you broke off your engagement in a two-line e-mail.
下一句歌词是什么
What was the next line?
我们能说些别的吗
Can we talk about something else?
-最经典的情歌  -嗨
- Greatest love song of all time. - Hey!
嘿  你们唱到德里克那段了没
Hey. Did you guys get to the part where Derek rhymes
"解剖课的总数"和"艾蒂逊美妙的臀部"
"Gross anatomy class" with "addison's fine ass"?
那段是我写的
'Cause i wrote that line.
-恩哼  -噢  我的错
- ahem. - Oh, my bad.
不不  没关系
No, no, it's fine.
听起来是首不错的歌
I, uh... I think it sounds Like a fine song.
阿尔奇  我听说你准备让德里克
Mm. Archie, I heard you were gonna let Derek
把这些寄生虫从你脑袋上拿掉
Remove those little suckers from your brain.
-有可能  -他是想这么干
- Maybe. - He is.
我讨厌外科  尤其是脑外科
I hate surgery, especially brain surgery.
是的  作为一个神经学专家
Yeah. Being a neurologist,
你有可能看到很多手术后的病人
You probably see a lot of patients post-op
他们就  在病房里炒鸡蛋
Who are just, you know, scrambled eggs up there--
好了  知道么  马克
Okay, you know what, mark?
你现在帮不上忙
You're not helping right now.
我们坐在这想说服他  手术是--
We're sitting here trying to convince him that surgery is--
不是一个好选择
Is not an option.
从这些扫描图上看
According to these scans,
你上次C. T检查中发现的那个囊肿
The single cyst that you had in your last c. t.
已经增加到了八个
Has now multiplied by eight,
阻塞了第三脑室
All clogging the third ventricle.
囊肿之间太纠结了
There's no way I can surgically navigate through a mess like that
我没有办法通过手术控制住
Without rupturing one.
这是什么意思
So what does that mean?
艾迪森  这有一屋子医生
You're in a room full of doctors, addison,
他们现在全都很安静
Who are all being very quiet right now.
我就要死了
I'm gonna die.
就是这个意思
That's what it means.
在你们每个人的信封里
Inside each one of your envelopes
是一个手术的名字
Is the name of a surgery.
你们的任务是在病人身上完成手术需要的遮盖
Your task is to drape your patients accordingly.
各就各位  预备  开始
On your marks. Get set. Go.
加油  大伙  放轻松
Come on, people. Lighten up.
这应该很好玩的  别这么紧张
This is supposed to be fun. Don't take it so seriously.
你真差劲  我奶奶都比你折得好
You suck at this! My grandmother could drape better than you.
抱歉  我会--我下次会做得更好
I'm sorry. I'll--i'll try To do better next time.
不不  我只是--你做得很棒
No, no. I'm just--You're doing great.
我--我不太会说话  我闹着玩呢  只不过
I'm--i'm trash-talking. I'm having fun. It's just--
我--真好玩
I'm--it's fun.
你在干嘛...
what do you...
-看上去不错  做得好  -完成
- Lookin' good. Good job. - Done.
好. .
Good...
-胆囊切除手术  -对  很好
- Laparoscopic cholecystectomy. - Yeah, that's good.
给你  下一个挑战
Here. Your, uh, next challenge.
我好了  我也做完了
Yes. Me, too. I'm done, too.
胰腺十二指肠切除术是胰腺癌的手术
A whipple is for pancreatic cancer.
你是打算从嘴巴里进去吗
Were you planning on going in through the mouth?
重来
Start over.
真的没有办法  艾迪
There's just no way, Addie.
我跟西德尔的卡纳和梅奥的拉里都谈过
I talked to Conroy at Cedars, Larry at Mayo,
他们也这么说  只会有--
And they agree. There'd just be--
我把你... 放进了一个...
I put... You in a...
小小的盒子里
Tiny box.
离婚以后  我把你变得...
After the divorce, I made you...
渺小又微不足道  没什么特别
Petty and inconsequential and nothing special
让你能挤进那个袖珍的... 小盒子
So that you could fit into this tiny... Little box
这使我每天有起床的动力
That would help me get out of bed in the morning.
但是现在...
But now...
现在我得把你从盒子里拿出来
Now i have to take you out of the box
因为... 我得去相信
Because... I need to believe that, uh,
你能做到
You can do this,
你能治好我哥哥
That you can save my brother.
我需要你变得无所不能
I need you to be a god.
就一天... 成为上帝
Just today... Be a god.
蒙特玛丽  阿奇尔
Uh, Montgomery, archer.
我是一个朋友
I'm a friend.
我是玛兰达·贝利  我是艾迪逊的朋友
I'm Dr. Miranda bailey. I'm a friend of Addison's.
哪个是你
Oh. Which one are you?
-什么  -阿奇尔是艾迪森的哥哥
- I'm sorry?- Archer is addison's brother,
阿奇尔的女朋友是艾迪森最好的朋友
And Archer's girlfriend is Addison's best friend,
她以前跟德里克最好的朋友结过婚
Who used to be married to Derek's best friend,
就是那个从德里克离婚后就没跟他说过话的
Who derek hasn't spoken to since the divorce.
对  对  那应该就是我  前夫
Right, right. Well, that would be me, the ex-husband.
萨姆·贝内特医生
Uh, Dr. Samuel bennett.
抱歉
Sorry.
我可不认为前夫
Well, i didn't think the ex-husband would show up
会来看前妻的男朋友
At the ex-wife's boyfriend's bedside.
对  别担心
Right. Don't worry about it.
我甚至不知道我为什么在这
Uh, even i don't know why i'm here.
但是  对了
But, uh, yeah.
三楼  3420病房
Third floor. Room 3420.
谢谢
Thank you.
贝内特医生
Dr. Bennett.
叫我萨姆
Uh, sam.
谢博德医生还在看扫描图
Dr. Shepherd is still studying the scans,
在找进行手术的方法
Looking for a way to operate,
但似乎很棘手
But it looks like a difficult case.
是的
Right.
嗨
Hey.
知道吗  艾迪森的哥哥可能治不好了
You know, Addison's brother probably isn't gonna make it.
他的囊肿不能动手术
His cysts are inoperable.
脑内蠕虫--不是件简单的事情
Worms in the brain--Not how you want to go.
我都不知道艾迪逊有个哥哥
I didn't even know Addison had a brother.
你能想象德里克在弹吉他的时候会说些话
I mean, you'd think Derek would've said something at some point
或者会唱些歌吗
Or sang something while he played his guitar.
说明白点
Speak english.
德里克弹过吉他
Oh, Derek used to play the guitar.
欧文的前未婚妻在医院里
Oh. Owen's ex-fiancee is in the hospital.
他从没告诉过我这个
Mm-hmm. His ex-fiancee he never told me about.
她怎么了
What's wrong with her?
她叫她爸爸"爹地"
Well, she calls her dad "daddy. "
不是  她怎么了
No. What's wrong with her?
她怎么在医院里
Why is she in the hospital?
她没怎么  是她爸爸
Oh, she isn't. Daddy is.
你应该去问问欧文
Hey, you know, you should ask owen
他会不会弹吉他
If he plays the guitar.
"找斯隆医生"
"find Dr. Sloan. "
"他是你的病人  询问他的症状"
"He's your patient. Ask him his symptoms. "
"正确地诊断他  然后接受下一个挑战"
"Diagnose him correctly to receive your next challenge. "
你的症状是什么
What are your symptoms?
现在我心跳很快
Well, right now i'm battling a rapid heart rate.
感觉满脸通红
I'm also feeling a little flushed.
更别提下半身的感觉了
I don't even want to mention what's going on below the belt.
别说了
Hey, no.
我-我-我再也不跟你龌龊秘密地调情了
I-i-i don't do dirty, secret flirting with you anymore.
我-我告诉过你  如果你愿意跟我
Okay? I-I told you, if you want to go public with me,
公开我们的恋情  我就公开和你龌龊地调情
With us, then i will do dirty, public flirting.
我的意思是  我会--我会公开调情  但不龌龊
I mean, i will--I will flirt publicly, not dirtily.
也许有那么点龌龊
Maybe a little dirtily.
你能--你能告诉我你的症状
Will you--would you please tell me your symptoms
让我集中精力吗
So i can concentrate?
"心动过速  血管性水肿"
"Tachycardia, angiodema"
"低血压  胸腹疼痛"
"Hypotension, severe chest and abdominal pain,
呼吸困难  咽喉--"  -过敏性休克
Difficulty breathing and throat clo--" - Anaphylactic shock!
犯规
Foul.
-什么  -你听到她的答案了
- What? - You heard her answer.
整个医院都听到她的答案了
Well, the whole hospital heard her answer.
你得保持足够的距离
Well, you shoulda kept a respectful distance.
新症状  重新开始
New symptoms. Resume play.
好了  你一定想问我话  问吧
All right. You must have questions, so ask.
他上次息肉切除术是什么时候
When was his last polypectomy?
既然你跟病人很熟悉
Since you're familiar with the patient.
-我不是这个意思  -我知道你是什么意思
- That's not what I meant. - No, I know what you meant.
-杨医生  你的症状是什么  -现在别来问
- Dr. Yang, what are your symptoms?- Now is not a good time.
"腹部有压迫感且感觉恶心
"heavy feeling in the abdomen accompanied by nausea
阴囊内有剧烈拉扯的感觉"
And acute pulling sensation in the scrotum. "
睾丸癌
Oh!Uh, testicular cancer.
克里斯蒂娜--
Cristina--
我得让怀特曼先生照CT
I have to get Mr. Whitman to c. t.
我在学校没心情做事  所以
I wasn't doing anyone any good at school, so...
欧文
Owen?
我不明白  什么...
I don't understand. What...
我在这里工作
I work here.
什-什么意思
Wh-what do you mean?
什么意思
What do you mean?
贝斯...
Beth...
你什么时候回来
When did you get back?
我-我-我刚看过你妈妈
I-I-I just saw your mom.
她不--
She didn't s--
我以为你还在伊拉克
I thought you were in Iraq.
我--我每天夜里都为你祈祷
I--I've been praying for you every night.
每天晚上我跪下来
Every night i'm on my knees
祈祷你能回来
Praying that y-you're gonna make it back,
祈祷你能活到明天
That you'll make it another 24 hours,
祈祷你能... 你能回家
That you'll... You'll make it home.
欧文  你回来了
Oh, owen. You're back.
她在干嘛
What is she doing?
好象是在祈祷
It looks like she's praying.
不  艾迪不祈祷的
Mm, no. Addie doesn't pray.
她在干嘛
What is she doing?
她在祈祷
Uh, she's praying.
不  艾迪不祈祷的
No, Addison doesn't pray.
她肯定在逃避
She must be hiding.
我听到了  我没有逃避
I can hear you. And i'm not hiding.
我想祈祷 但不知怎么做
I am trying to pray, but i don't know how to pray
因为我现在很暴躁  我们只在圣诞的时候去教堂
Because i'm a wasp, and we only go to church on christmas.
你们走吧  我来
You guys go. I got this.
我跟上帝没打过交道
I have no clout with god.
他甚至不知道我是谁
God doesn't even know who i am,
这真糟  因为我得
Which sucks, because I could...
我需要一些帮助
I could use some help.
仁慈的天父  我需要你的指引
Dear god, I need your guidance.
我亲了一个儿科医生
I kissed a peds surgeon.
你亲了个儿科医生
You kissed a peds surgeon?
我从没想过最后会跟一个女人在一起  上帝啊
I never thought i'd end up with a woman, god,
但是--我意思是--直到最近--
But--i mean, not until lately--
但--问题不在这里
But that--that's not the problem.
问题是关于儿科这个东西  她总是很活泼
The problem is the peds thing. She's--she's perky...
好象她的头巾上有蝴蝶在飞一样
And has butterflies on her scrub cap.
但是她也... 也很性感...
But she's... Also hot...
真的很性感
Really hot.
所以
So...
帮我把这些蝴蝶赶走
Help me get over the butterflies.
阿门
Amen.
你是个很棒的医生  你救了很多孩子
You're an amazing doctor. You save babies.
上帝知道你是谁
God knows who you are.
你真的相信这个吗...
Do you really believe in all this...
上帝
In god?
有时候
Sometimes.
很多的时候
Well... Most of the time,
当它实现的时候
When it counts.
你的妻子现在在小教堂里祈祷
Your wife's in the chapel praying.
她不是我的妻子
She's not my wife,
她也不祈祷
And she doesn't pray.
-你还好吗  -嗨
- How are you?- Hey.
太好了
- Good. - Oh. Ah!
你知道的  中年危机
Oh, you know, midlife crisis.
-我打了个耳洞  打了个耳洞  -哈哈
- I got an earring. I got an earring. - Uh-huh.
第二天我就让它堵上了
But i-i let the hole close up the very next day.
应该很好看
Oh, that woulda--woulda been a good look on you.
我见到了  梅瑞迪斯
I met, uh, meredith.
哈哈
Uh-huh.
她可不是中年危机
She's not a midlife crisis.
她是实实在在的
She's the real thing.
太好了  我为你高兴
That's great. I'm happy for you, man.
我为你高兴
I'm happy for you.
是啊
yeah.
-我应该打电话的  -不
- I shoulda called. - No.
我们应该保持联络的  这是我的错
No, I should've stayed in touch. It's my fault.
人们会动  会改变  我们都是这样
Hey, people move, they change. You know, we all did.
对
Yeah.
所以... 是啊
So... But yeah.
她在祈祷
She's praying.
对
Yeah.
她希望能有奇迹
She's expecting a miracle...
可我不能创造一个给她
And I can't deliver one.
我见过颅内长囊肿的病人
I've seen patients with one cyst in the ventricle,
也有长两个的
Maybe two.
他有八个
He has eight.
显示器不可能不弄破囊肿
There is no way i can get a scope in there
放进去
Without rupturing one.
太多了
There's too many.
可能是你离的太近了
Maybe you're just too close to it.
如果这里只有一个呢
What if there were Just one?
你知道  跟我说一下你会怎么移除
You know, explain to me How you would remove
那一个
Just that one.
血压110/80
110 over 80.
赢了有什么奖品
What's the prize For winning?
他们需要奖励一下
They need a prize.
会有奖品的  很棒的奖品
They're getting a prize, A really big prize.
我需要奖品
I need a prize.
怎么回事
What's going on?
我的病人需要放松一下
Uh, my patients needed A distraction,
伊兹需要一个活的病人
And, uh, izzie needed Real patients.
进行的顺利吗  很顺利  太好玩了
So how's it going?It's going great. Super fun.
我们都很开心
We're having a lot of fun.
格蕾医生  天哪  我现在要做手术了
Dr. Grey. Oh, my god. Am i going to surgery now?
随时都有可能 珍
Could be any time now, jen.
怎么了
What?
我找不到
I can't find it.
等等  有什么不对劲吗
Wait... Is something wrong?
孩子的心脏不跳了吗  什么
Is the baby's heart Not beating? What--
那是孩子的屁股
You're on the kid's ass.
心脏在这边
The heart's over here.
谢天谢地
Thank god.
不是你想的那样
It's not what you think.
我保证
I can guarantee
我不是你想的那种混球
I'm not as much of an ass As you think i am.
你妈知道你回来了吗
does your mother know you're back?
检查完了呼我
Page me when this is done.
好吧  阿切尔  我要在颅内创造点空间
All right, archer. I need to Create room in the ventricle
这样就可以把显示器放进去  如果给每一个囊肿放气
So i can maneuver the scope. If i deflate each cyst,
显示器可以将他们一个一个的移走
The scope can remove them One by one.
囊肿会弄破的
The cysts will rupture.
我会用钳子把他们夹住  然后提起来
I'm gonna grab each one With forceps, pull it up
拖到口边  把液体吸出来
To the edge of the port And suction out the fluid.
-引流液体应该说的更清楚点  -我会的
- The suction would Have to be precise  - It will be.
-你做不来的  -不  我可以
- You can't do it. - Well, i think i can.
理论上可以控制囊肿的破裂方式
Basically you can control The way the cyst ruptures?
不  他不行
No, he can't.
听着  我知道你们想降低风险  但是
Look, i know you guys want me to go down fighting, but i--
懦夫
Coward.
你说什么
Excuse me?
我叫你"懦夫"  你是个十足的懦夫
I said "coward. " You're a coward by trade.
你是个神经病学家  是我们的前辈
You're a neurologist. You guys feed off us,
给我们讲你的病例  假设可能出现的后果
Refer your patients to us, let Us assume the responsibility,
如果老天要阻止这一切发生  好吧
And if god forbid Something happens, well...
我告诉你  我来承担责任
I'll tell you what, i can Assume the responsibility.
儿科研究奖学金
Peds surgery fellowship?
对  快把我的外科住院
Yep, Just when i'm almost done
实习总结写完了
With my general surgery Residency.
疯狂吗
Crazy, huh?
不是  是惊讶
No, just, uh... Surprising.
我看你不像是儿科医生
Uh, you don't seem like A-a peds person to me.
为什么不像
Why not?
应为你从来不笑
Because you don't smile.
儿科医生总是笑容满面
Peds people smile.
我会笑
I smile.
我现在没打算笑  可我是会笑的
Well i'm not going to smile Rit now, but i do smile.
我经常笑
I smile frequently.
他已经准备好了
Hey. He under yet?
是的
Yeah.
儿科研究奖学金
A peds surgery Fellowship?
我有小孩的  很喜欢孩子
I have a child. I'm familiar with children.
我会是个出色的儿科医生
I am going to be An excellent pediatric surgeon.
你在孩子面前
You're gonna want to keep
也会是这个臭脾气
That temper in check Around the kids.
阿奇尔躺在手术台上看起来很怪
Weird seeing archie On that table.
我有哮喘
Asthma.
好像里面没药了
Looks like i'm low.
克莱斯  帮贝尼特医生把这个装满
Krez, refill this For dr. Bennett here.
多谢
Thanks.
事实证明
It's good practice.
哮喘对孩子而言是件大事
Asthma's big With the kids.
开始吧  德里克  快点开始啊
Say it, derek. Come on, say it.
快点  快点  快点
Say it. Say it. Say it.
各位
Okay, everybody.
今天是救死扶伤的好日子
It's a beautiful day To save lives.
手术刀
Scalpel.
你总得告诉她的
at some point, You're gonna have to tell her.
我们说的是贝斯
This is beth We're talking about.
有个学生擤鼻涕
She worries herself sick
她就会担心自己被传染
When one of her students Gets the sniffles.
接受不了坏消息
She can't handle bad news.
她是个阳光女孩儿
She's a sunshine girl.
你应该很了解她的
And you used to know that About her.
好吧  她最后还是会知道的
Well, she'll find out Eventually.
杨医生
dr. Yang.
什么事  露丝  呼叫主任  预定手术室
What's going on?Ruth, call the chief And reserve an o. r.
欧文  这是
Owen--It's a...
是并发症  需要手术
I-it's a complication. He needs surgery.
可是
But what...
这是什么的并发症啊
A c--a complication From what?
他会没事的
He's gonna be okay.
我会及时告诉你情况的  走吧
I'll keep you updated. Let's go.
好的  进入第三脑室
okay, Entering the third ventricle.
好的  固定一号囊肿
All right. Securing cyst number one.
放气
Deflating cyst one.
好的  吸
All right. Suction.
囊肿有什么症状吗
Any sign of the scolex?
就这个
there it is.
一次取一个
one at a time.
一次一个
One at a time.
好了
Okay.
我需要分分心
I need to be distracted.
随便谁  谈谈其他的事儿吧
Someone, um, talk About something other than
不是关于我哥的就行
What's going on With my brother right now.
马克很健谈的
Uh, mark is good At talking about himself.
事实上  我在用内诊镜检查实施
Actually, i've been Using endoscopy
头和脖子部位的癌症切除
For head and neck Cancer resections,
如果我能关注病人的标准
And if i could just focus The criteria for patients,
我会有很大的突破
I might have a breakthrough On my hands.
你怎么回事
What happened to you?
他在和某人交往
He met someone.
格蕾医生
dr. Grey.
托瑞斯医生说我必须吃东西  不好意思
Dr. Torres said i, uh, Had to eat. I'm sorry.
没关系  好吃吗
No, it's okay. How is it?
很好吃
It's amazing.
对不起  对不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
太难吃了  什么味儿都没有
It's bland. It's really bland.
我现在要做手术
Oh! I need my surgery, now!
这算什么医院
What kind of hospital is this?
我得等多长时间
How long am i supposed to wait?
住口
Look, stop it!
听着
Look, uh...
如果你不冷静下来
If you don't settle down,
你的血压就会上升
Your blood pressure's Gonna rise,
你就会开始宫缩
And you're gonna start Contracting.
抱歉  我不认识你
I'm sorry Because i don't know you,
可你必须闭嘴  明白吗
But you really need To shut up, okay?
好吧
All right.
在这
There.
看啊
Look.
这是你孩子的脸
There's your son's face.
为了他你要再坚持
That's what you need To hold on to
几个小时  可以吗
For the next couple Of hours, okay?
看看这儿
Let's see here.
这... 这是肿瘤吗
Is--is that a tumor?
他需要更多积极的治疗
He's gonna need More aggressive treatment.
必须让他女儿知道
He'll have to tell His daughter now.
他不会的
he won't.
她幼年丧母
Her mother died When she was little.
他认为这是难以承受的伤痛
He feels that's enough sadness For anyone,
所以  他一直在保护她
So... He sheltered her.
给她买好车  贵衣服
She always had a nice car, Nice clothes,
她想要的一切
Anything she wanted.
她迟早会知道的
Well, she'll find out Eventually.
以前她会跟我哭诉
She used to call me in tears
她的公寓里有蜘蛛
When there was a spider In her apartment.
这成了我跟迈克之间的笑料
It became a joke between Michael and i.
我俩从来都不会同时离开镇上
Neither of us could be Out of town at the same time
以防贝斯发现了虫子
In case beth found a bug.
如果他需要化疗
Well, when he needs To go through chemo
或者病入膏肓  需要临终关怀
Or gets so sick He needs hospice care,
当一切结束的时候  她会发现的
She'll find out When it's already over.
她应该知道的
She deserves more than that.
好的  格蕾医生  几个了
okay, dr. Grey, what's the number?
七个囊肿  七条囊虫
Seven cysts, Seven scolexes.
好的  再来一个
Okay, then one more.
该死
Damn it.
心率降低了
He's getting bradycardic.
我需要冲洗  看看水流会不会被截住
i need to irrigate, See if the flow is blocked.
心搏停止
asystole.
打开计时器
Start the code clock.
德里克  心跳停止了
Derek, asystole.
到底哪去了
Where the hell is it?
去拿急救车  开始按压
Get the crash cart. Starting compressions.
不  谁都不许动
No! Stop! Nobody move.
不能按压  我得把虫子找出来
We can't start compressions. I need to find the worm.
可他
But he's--
我们还有两三分钟  都别动
We have two minutes, maybe Three. Nobody move. Just stop.
心脏停跳多久了
how long Has he been down?
两分二十秒
2 minutes, 20 seconds.
在那儿
there it is.
抓住了
got it
该死
damn it
要开始分裂了
It's starting to tear apart.
也许我该旋转  然后反向把它拖出来
Maybe if i just rotate it And reverse it back.
第八个
and that's number eight.
心率恢复了
Heart rate's coming back up.
好的
okay.
多谢  各位
Thank you, everybody.
你们让我的朋友们很高兴
you just made some friends of mine very happy.
刚做完手术  怎么回事
I just got out of surgery. What's going on?
随时都可能发生
Could be any minute now.
她需要奖励
She needs a prize.
很大的奖励  可不要太大
A big prize, But not too big,
因为他们还没有得到自己的阑尾
Because they did take out Their own appendixes.
我知道他们还在被那件事惩罚
And i understand they're still Being punished for that
你知道他们不该只是
And that you think They're not even qualified
拿着钳子 所以
To hold a clamp, so...
-您有类似的奖励吗  -多谢
- Do you have any prizes Like that?- Thank you.
他们刚诊断了最后一个病人
They just got their symptoms From their final patients.
拉好终点线  马上就过来了
Get out the finish line. It's gonna be close.
来了
here they come!
不错  不错  不错  加油  快跑
all right, all right, All right! Come on, run!
快啊  快啊
Come on! Come on!
加油  加油  把结果给我  快啊
Come on, come on!Bring it in!Move! Move!
乔治
George?
三人并列
3-way tie.
好吧  最后一个病人的诊断是什么
Okay, final patient diagnosis.
-运动障碍  -不对
- Motion sickness!- No
-登革热  -不是
- Dengue fever!- No.
-脑囊尾蚴病  -正确
- Neurocysticercosis!-yay!
女士们先生们  冠军诞生了
ladies and gentlemen, We have a winner.
做得好
Nicely done.
等一下  奖品是什么
Wait, what's the prize?
你可以参加谢博德指导的颅骨切开术
You get to scrub in On shepherd's craniotomy...
手持那个终极插管
And hold the doomsday sucker.
-什么是终极插管? -终极插管?
What's the doomsday sucker?Doomsday sucker?
真的是肥虫呀
It's just a really big sucker.
手术很困难
It was a hard surgery.
部分肠坏死  正如我们所料
Some of the bowel was dead, As we suspected,
我们已经成功的切除了病变部分
But we were able to remove The diseased part successfully.
他现在还在昏迷中
He's in recovery,
一小时内你就可以看望他了
And you can see him In about an hour.
这一点也不像你
You don't even Look like yourself.
你说什么
Excuse me?
完全不像你
You don't.
你变得... 很努力
You look... Hard.
很...
And...
我了解在这里工作不是件易事
Look, i-i know it-- It wasn't easy over there.
我听说有些人回来后
I-i hear People come back and...
我知道不能祈求你一回来
I know You can't just come back
就使生活走上正轨  但是
And be normal right away, But--
他还会睡上几个小时
He'll be asleep For a couple of hours,
你现在就可以看望他了
But you can see him now.
分隔两地就靠邮件交流
Two lines in an e-mail?
我们之间不应该只是这样
I deserve more than that.
贝斯  你爸得的是直肠癌
Beth, your dad Has colorectal cancer.
他已经接受过放射疗法
He's already been through Radiation treatment
和息肉切除治疗
And polyp removals.
他并没有告诉你
He didn't tell you...
因为他不想增加你的负担
'Cause he didn't want To burden you.
他情愿独自承受痛苦
He'd like to spare you Any pain...
不管苦海多深
Any more pain.
这些都是他的朋友
He had all these friends.
他们一起高歌一起弹吉他
They sang And they played guitar and...
似乎他完全变成了另外一个人
It's almost like he was A totally different person.
没错  他就是这样的
Well, he was.
这还真有点吓到我了
It kinda freaks me out A little bit.
感觉我其实并不了解他
I feel like I don't know him.
其实我也不了解欧文
And i don't know owen.
同时天涯沦落人
We don't.
我们都没有真正了解他们
We don't know them.
赛迪  赛迪
Sadie. Sadie, hey.
等一下  等一下
Hold up. Hold up. Hold up.
我只是想让你知道
I just wanted To let you know, um,
我很乐于帮助你  如果你不介意的话
I'm happy to help you If you'd like--
比如复习下基础知识
You know, Reviewing the basics
-或者在实验室里互相督促  -你说什么
- Or putting in some Supervised skills lab hours. - Excuse me?
我曾经是个留级实习生
Well, i... I was a repeater Earlier this year.
我知道放松就会落后
I know how easy it is To get behind.
我不需要你来做我的导师
I don't need a tutor.
真的吗
You don't?
不需要
No.
在这个节骨眼上
At this point In your training,
你应该做的是聆听症状
You should be able To hear symptoms,
诊断病因
Diagnose the problem
然后做出是否手术的结论
And decide whether or not A patient needs surgery.
你能做到吗
Can you do that?
行吗
Can you?
病人信任你
Because they think you can,
你不得不置身于
And they will put you In situations
各种紧急状况下
Where you have to.
赛迪  你这样做会伤害病人
Sadie, You could hurt someone.
是我打给她的
I call her. All right?
我每星期打给我妈一通电话
I call my mother Once a week.
我没有告诉她我回来了
I haven't told her That i'm back.
所以她以为我还在那
She thinks That i'm calling from...
我尽量长话短说
I keep The conversations short
是因为我无法忍受她知道
Because i can't bear For her to know
自己儿子突然回来后的那种表现
That the s She sent off to war is gone.
就因为我回来了
He's gone.
如果就那样上车
And if i just got in my car
驾驶6英里去看她的话
And drove the six miles To see her,
她一定会很难过
She'd be so sad,
她会像贝斯那样
And she would look at me
看着我
The same way That beth does now...
好像我并没有回来一样
Like i'm not there.
就只有你看着我时
The only time I don't feel like a ghost
我才不会感觉自己像鬼魂
Is when you look at me
因为你是用心在看我
Because you look at me And you see me.
用心在看
You see me.
这才是我要的
This is me.
求你了  克里斯蒂娜  看着我
Please, cristina, see me.
看着我
See me.
珍 抱歉打扰
Jen, i am so sorry.
我把你的手术排在了明天第一场
I have you scheduled for First thing tomorrow morning.
德里克
Derek...
我直接称呼你名吧
Uh, i'm using Your first name now...
因为我挺喜欢你的
Because i like you a lot
我想我们应该能成为朋友
And i'm starting to Consider us friends,
-所以我想直接称呼你的名  叫你德里克  -好啊
- So i'm using your first name And i'm calling you derek. - Okay.
德里克  我想求你件事
And, derek, i'm begging you,
求你  千万别让我再苦等一天了
Please, please, please don't Make me wait another night.
她是个好女孩
She's good.
你绝不会拒绝和这样的女孩结婚的
Try being married to her. You'll never say no again.
格蕾医生
Dr. Grey.
这个奖你是实至名归的
It would appear that Congratulations are in order.
谢谢  斯隆医生
Thank you, dr. Sloan.
我想澄清下
I'd also Like it acknowledged
我给你的祝贺词
That i offer These congratulations
是出于专业和尊敬的角度
Professionally And respectfully...
绝没有隐含任何不恰当身体语言的含义
Without any innuendo Or inappropriate body language.
这点我承认  斯隆医生
Acknowledged, dr. Sloan.
你知不知道
Do you know,
什么叫终极插管
Um... What's a doomsday sucker?
艾迪森·蒙哥马利
Addison montgomery.
莱西·格蕾
Uh, l-lexie grey.
马克  艾迪  小格蕾  -格蕾的妹妹  是的
- Mark, addie, little grey. -Little grey? Ahem.
待会儿在乔的酒吧和你碰头
I am gonna have to meet you At joe's in a bit.
我有一个 穿颅术  小格蕾
I have a craniotomy. Little grey, i hear
-你来拿终极插管  -现在吗
- You're gonna be holding The doomsday sucker. - Now?
-好的  棒极了  -二号手术室见
- Great. Yeah, yeah, yes. Yes. Yes, sir. okay. - O. r. Two. i'll see you there.
终极插管
Doomsday sucker!
小格蕾  太难以置信了
Can you believe little grey And, uh--
你有没有听说德里克准备向梅瑞迪斯求婚的消息
Hey, did you hear derek was Gonna propose to meredith?
-你觉得怎样  -我得赶手术了
- How about that? - And i'm off to surgery.
干嘛
What?
伊兹  你到底怎么了
Iz... What's going on With you?
没啥  我很好啊
Nothing. I'm fine.
正如你所见  实习生并不是一群失败者
You saw. The interns Are not a bunch of losers.
他们也是有想法的
They know things.
他们会成为好的医生的
They're gonna make Good doctors.
真的  我很好
Really, i'm fine.
我真的没事
I'm fine.
她一无所知  完全不懂
She knows nothing. Just... Nothing.
她对病人只会是个危害
She's a danger to the patients,
所以我告诉她去跟主任谈谈
And so i told her that she Could tell the chief or i could,
你是她的朋友  所以我想让你知道这件事
And i wanted to let you know Because you're her friend.
尽管之前
Although for the life of me,
我并不知道你们以前是朋友
I... I don't know How you two were ever friends.
怎么样了
What happened?
我退出了
I quit.
欧麦利简直就是个小特警
O'malley's a little narc.
我情愿做一个懦者也不要做一个骗子
I'd rather be deemed A quitter than a cheater.
难道你以前没有欺骗过吗
Did you cheat your way Into the program?
我并不是个高学历者
Listen, i'm not book smart.
你知道的
You know that.
我脚踏实地地学习
I learn on my feet.
我傻傻得以为只要和你呆在一起
I thought if i came to where You were, you could...
就可以帮你共渡难关嘛
Pull you through.
我们共同经历了很多风雨
We've seen each other Through a lot.
我们不再是一心幻想着去欧洲的25岁傻女孩了
We're not 25, sleeping our way Through europe anymore.
我们可以的
We could though.
想想  我们可以今晚登上飞机
Think about it. We could get On a plane tonight.
去
We could go--
不行  我不能  我得工作
No, no. I can't. I have to work.
我不能就...
I can't just...
你知道吗
Wow, you know...
你的生活都被他们糟蹋了
They've sucked the life Right out of you.
我以前认识的那个梅丽迪斯
The meredith i used to know--
我就是我  我就在这
Is right here. I'm here.
我只是不想再一路睡遍欧洲了
I just don't want to sleep My way through europe anymore.
我想在这呆着
I want to be here.
我想呆这
插管[同"老二"音]准备好了吗
Sucker at the ready?
插管准备就绪
Sucker's at the ready.
你在拿我开刷
You're mocking me.
就意思一下  该死
Only a little. Damn it.
-该死  -发生什么了
- Damn it. - What, what happened?
心率88超过60了  输2单位的血
B. p. 's 88 over 60. Hang 2 units of blood.
好的  言归正传
Okay, all joking aside,
-格蕾医生  插入插管  -好的  我的天
- Dr. Grey, Bring in the doomsday sucker. - Okay. Oh, my god. Okay.
就是这  伸进去  然后放在这
Right in here. Get in there. Put it right in there. Wow.
用临时夹子
Temporary clips. Wow.
开始显微缝线
Microsutures, please.
血压110/72
B. p. Is 110 over 72.
好了  把插管拔出
Okay, get the sucker Out of there.
就这样吗  行了吗
Is that it? Did you--did you get it?
缝得很好
There's good flow.
我们完成了
Yes, we did it.
这次经历教会我
And that will teach me Never to mock
永远不要再嘲笑热切的实习生
An eager young intern again.
-你就是一混蛋  -我不应该这么脱口而出的
-You are such an ass. - I shouldn't have blurted.
小小的警告其实也不错
Y--a little warning Would have been nice.
你还好吗
But you're okay?
感觉怪怪的
You know, it's strange.
我期待会有那种很糟糕的感觉
I... I expected this Horrible feeling,
那种一波又一波的悲伤和失落感
This wave of sadness Or something to just take over,
但是  当人们离婚后
But... People get divorced...
他们又认识新人  然后又再结婚
They meet new people, They remarry.
我不懂
I don't know.
也许  只是看到阿奇尔在手术室
You know, maybe it's just... Seeing archer in that O. R. ,
好像我整个
It just... Changed my perspective
观点都被改变了
Or something.
我看你还是蛮希望一切回归如初的
But you sort of wished It'd been you first.
你给我闭嘴
Oh, shut it.
那又怎样  难道你打算告诉德里克
So what, are you gonna Tell derek about the--
好吧  等下  等下
Okay, wait, wait.
如果我们把梅丽迪斯当成个12岁孩童
If we call meredith The 12 year old,
-那我们又怎么称呼莱西呢  难道是学龄前儿童  -她可是个女人了
- What--what do we call lexie, A preschooler? - She's a woman.
好吧  我打算告诉他
oh, okay. And i'm gonna tell him.
我认真的
I'm working on it. Mm-hmm.
他来了
There he is! Hey!
你也来了  看来我很受欢迎嘛
Oh, there you go. That's The kind of welcome i deserve.
乔  为神经学上帝开瓶威士忌
Joe, Scotch for the neuro god.
你今天表现得就像上帝
You... You were a god today.
你是手术室里的上帝
You were a god in that O. R.
你犹如游龙戏水
You slew dragons, You walked on water. You...
你就像个上帝一样  但是现在
You were a god, but now...
你又得重新变得袖珍
Now you need to get Very tiny again...
然后回到那个小盒子里去啦
And go back in the box.
-你的开颅术做得怎样  -很好
- How--how was your craniotomy? - It was fine.
-是吗  -我救了阿奇尔
- Yeah? - Yeah, and i stopped in On archer on my way out.
总之一切都很好
Things are, uh, good. Good.
*had his Mitral valve gotten too thick?
*is that what made The cadaver so sick?  so sick
当是我们不能
Oh. but we can't--
等下  我们忘词了  后面是
Wait, we can't Remember the chorus. Come on.
"we got all the way Through the second verse"
不  是的
No. No. Yes, yes.
-副歌是以你的名字开头的  你的名字  -是的
- Your name starts the chorus. Your name - Yes, yes.
*addison montgomery
*he met her in the summery
不是"summery. "  我从不会拿它当名词用
It wasn't "summery. " i'd never Use summery as a noun.
是"I met her... In the summer, She... "
I met her... In the summer, She...
"summer, she"  真的吗
Oh, summer, she--really?
是的  是"summer, she, "
yeah. "summer, she, " well.
编得妙  "She was...
That's clever. She was...
"cting up A very dead body" 这就是我不联系的原因
cting up A very dead body  This is why I don't stay in touch.
*and in her eyes, I saw my life
*i knew that she would be My wife
*and she would breathe The life back into me
*for every day Until eternity
*or until i'd be
*as dead as that body
*body
妈呀  真有你的
Ah, jeez. Yeah, you got it.
该你了 该你了
There you go. There you go.
怎么回事  呼谢博德  快!
what's happening? Page shepherd, now!